College English Test, Band 6, Part 2, Listening Comprehension.
Section A, Directions.
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1, with a single line through the
centre. Conversation 1.
What's all that?
Are you going to a salad?
No, I'm going to make a gazpacho.
What's that? Gazpacho is a cold soup from Spain.
It's mostly vegetables.
I guess you could call it a liquid salad.
Cold soup? Sounds weird.
It's delicious, trust me.
I tried it for the first time during my summer vacation in Spain.
You see, in the south of Spain, it gets very hot in the summer, up to 40 degrees
Celsius. So a cold gazpacho is very refreshing.
The main ingredients are tomato, cucumber, bell peppers, olive oil and stale bread.
Stale bread? Surely you mean bread for dipping into the soup.
No, bread is crushed and blended in like everything else.
It adds texture and thickness to the soup.
And is it healthy?
Sure. As I said earlier, it's mostly vegetables.
You can also add different things if you like, such as hard -boiled egg or cured
ham. Cured ham?
What's that? That's another Spanish delicacy.
Have you never heard of it?
It's quite famous.
No. Is it good too?
Oh yeah, definitely.
It's amazing. It's a little dry and salty and it's very expensive because it comes
from a special type of pig that only eats a special type of food.
The ham is covered in salt to dry and preserve it and left to hang for up to two
years. It has a very distinct flavor.
Hmm, sounds interesting.
Where can I find some?
It used to be difficult to get Spanish produce here, but it's now a lot more common.
Most large supermarket chains have cured ham in little packets, but in Spain you can
buy a whole leg.
A whole pig leg?
Why would anybody want so much ham?
In Spain, many people buy a whole leg for special group events such as Christmas.
They cut it themselves into very thin slices with a long flat knife.
Questions one to four are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question one. What do we learn about gazpacho?
Question two. For what purpose is stale bread mixed into gazpacho?
Question three. Why does the woman think gazpacho is healthy?
Question four. What does the woman say about cured ham?
Conversation two. I wish to buy a of wine.
Hi, yes. What kind of wine would you like?
I don't know.
Sorry, I don't know much about wine.
That's no problem at What's the occasion and how much would you like to spend?
It's for my boss.
It's his birthday.
I know he likes wine, but I don't know what type.
I also do not want anything too expensive, maybe mid -range.
How much would you say is a mid -range bottle of wine, approximately?
Well, it varies greatly.
Our lowest prices are around six dollars a bottle, but those are table wines.
They are not very special and I would not suggest them as a gift.
On the other end, our most expensive bottles are over a hundred and fifty dollars.
If you are looking for something priced in the middle, I would say anything between
thirty dollars and sixty dollars would make a decent gift.
How does that sound?
Hmm, yeah. I guess something in the vicinity of thirty or forty would be good.
Which type would you recommend?
I would say the safest option is always a red wine.
They are generally more popular than whites and can usually be paired with food more
easily. Our specialty here are Italian wines and these tend to be fruity with medium
acidity. This one here is a Chianti, which is perhaps Italy's most famous type of
red wine. Alternatively, you may wish to try and surprise your boss with something
less common, such as this Zinvantelle.
The grapes are originally native to Croatia, but this winery is in eastern Italy and
it has a more spicy and peppery flavour.
So, to summarise, the Chianti is more classical and the Zinvantelle more exciting.
Both are similarly priced at just under forty dollars.
I will go with Chianti then.
Thanks. five to eight are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question five. What does the woman think of table wines?
Question six. What is the price range of wine the man will consider?
Question seven. Why does the woman recommend red wines?
Question eight. What do we learn about the wine the man finally bought?
Section B. Directions.
this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one with a single line through
the centre. Passage one.
Many people enjoy secret codes.
The harder the code, the more some people will try to figure it out.
In wartime, codes are especially important.
They help armies send news about battles and the size of enemy forces.
Neither side wants its code broken by the other.
One very important code was never broken.
It was used during World War II by the Americans.
It was a spoken code, never written down, and it was developed and used by Navajo
Indians. They were called the Navajo Code Talkers.
The Navajos created the in their own language.
Navajo is hard to learn, and only a few people know it.
So it was pretty certain that the enemy would not be able to understand the Code
Talkers. In addition, the Talkers used code words.
They called a submarine an iron fish and a small bomb thrown by hand a potato.
If they wanted to spell something, they used code words for letters of the alphabet.
For instance, the letter A was ant or apple or axe.
The Code Talkers worked mostly in the islands in the One or two would be assigned to
a group of They would send messages by field telephone to the Code Talker in the
next group, and he would relay the information to his commander.
The Code Talkers played an important part in several battles.
They helped troops coordinate their movements and attacks.
After the war, the U.S.
government honored them for what they had accomplished.
Theirs was the most successful wartime code ever used.
Question 10. What do we learn about the Navajo Code Talkers?
Question 11. What is the speaker mainly talking about?
Passage 2. If you are young and thinking about your career, you'll want to know
where you can make a living.
Well, there's going to be a technological replacement of a lot of knowledge
-intensive jobs in the next 20 years, particularly in the two largest sectors of the
labor force with professional skills.
One is teaching, and the other, healthcare.
You have so many applications and software and platforms that are going to come in
and provide information and service in these two fields.
Which means a lot of healthcare and education sectors will be radically changed, and
a lot of jobs will be lost.
Now, where will the new jobs be found?
Well, the one sector of the economy that can't be easily duplicated by even smart
technologies is the caring sector, the personal care sector.
That is, you can't really get a robot to do a great massage or physical therapy, or
you can't get the kind of personal attention you need with regard to therapy or any
other personal service.
There could be very high -end personal services.
Therapists do charge a lot of money.
I think there's no limit to the amount of personal attention and personal care
people would like if they could afford it.
But the real question in the future is, how can people afford these things if they
don't have money, because they can't get a job that pays enough?
That's why I wrote this book, which is about how to reorganize the economy for the
future when technology brings about disruptive changes to what we used to consider
high -income work.
Question 13. Where will young people have more chances to find jobs?
Question 14. What does the speaker say about therapists?
Question 15. What is the speaker's book about?
Section C. Directions.
In this section, will hear three recordings of lectures or talks, followed by three
or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices,
marked A, B, C and D.
Then, mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one, with a single line through
the centre. Recording One.
American researchers have discovered the world's paved road, a 4,600 -year -old
highway. It linked a stone pit in the Egyptian desert to waterways that carried
blocks to monument sites along the Nile.
The eight -mile road is at least 500 years older than any previously discovered
road. It is the only paved road discovered in ancient Egypt, said geologist Thomas
Bowne of the United States Geological Survey.
He reported the discovery on Friday.
The road probably doesn't rank with the pyramids as a construction feat, but it is a
major engineering achievement, said his colleague, geologist James Harrell of the
University of Toledo.
Not only is the road earlier than we thought possible, we didn't even think they
built roads. The researchers also made a discovery in the stone pit at the northern
end of the road, the first evidence that the Egyptians used rock saws.
This is the oldest example of saws being used for cutting stone, said Bowne's
colleague, James Hoffmeyer, of Wheaton College in Illinois.
That's two technologies we didn't know they had, Harrell said,
and we don't know why they were both abandoned.
road was discovered in the Fiam depression, about 45 miles southwest of Cairo.
Short segments of the road had been observed by earlier explorers, said, but they
failed to realize its significance or follow up on their observations.
Bowne and his colleagues stumbled across it while they were doing geological mapping
in the region.
The road was clearly built to provide services for the newly discovered stone pit.
Bowne and Harrell have found the camp that housed workers at the stone pit.
The road appears today to go nowhere, ending in the middle of the desert.
When it was built, its terminal was a on the shore of Lake Moiris,
which had an elevation of about 66 feet above sea level, the same as the dock.
Lake Moiris received its water from the annual floods of the Nile.
At the time of the floods, the river and lake were at the same level and connected
through a gap in the hills near the modern villages of El Lajun and Hawara.
Harrell and Bowne believe that blocks were loaded onto barges during the dry season,
then floated over to the Nile during the floods to be shipped off to the monument
sites at Giza and Question 16 to 18 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 16. What do we learn from the lecture about the world's oldest paved road
in Egypt? Question 17.
What did the researchers discover in the stone pit?
Question 18. For what purpose was the road built?
Question For what purpose was the paved road built?
Question 18. For what purpose was the paved road built?
Question 18. For what purpose was the road built?
Acupuncture points are stimulated to balance the circulation of qi.
The truth is, though, acupuncture is at least 2,200 years old.
Nobody really knows what's happening, says Paul Zumewski, a PhD in Chinese studies
who practices acupuncture in Philadelphia.
Question 19. What does the speaker find especially strange?
Question 20. Why did the speaker go see Dr.
Question 21. What accounts for the growing popularity of acupuncture in the United
States, according to the speaker?
Question 21. What the growing popularity of acupuncture in They uncovered clues to
what was going wrong by researching a fascinating subject,
how birth order affects not only your personality, but also how compatible you are
with your mate.
Question popularity of acupuncture in the United States, according to the speaker?
The oldest tends to be self -assured, responsible,
a high achiever, and relatively serious and reserved.
He may be slow to make friends, perhaps content with only one companion.
The best matches are with a youngest, an only, or a mate raised in a large family.
The worst match is with another oldest, since the two will be too sovereign to share
a household comfortably.
The youngest child of the family thrives on attention and tends to be outgoing,
adventurous, optimistic, creative and less ambitious than others in the family.
He may lack self -discipline and have difficulty making decisions on his own.
A youngest brother of brothers, often unpredictable and romantic, will match best
with an oldest sister of brothers.
The youngest sister of brothers is best matched with an oldest brother of sisters,
who will happily indulge these traits.
The middle child is influenced by many variables, however, middles are less likely
to take initiative and more anxious and self -critical than others.
Middles often successfully marry other middles, since both are strong on tact, not
so strong on aggressiveness, and tend to crave affection.
The only child is often most comfortable when alone, but since an only tends to be a
well -adjusted individual,
she'll eventually learn to relate to any chosen spouse.
The male only child expects his wife to make life easier without getting much in
return. He is sometimes best matched with a younger sister of brothers.
The female only child, who tends to be slightly more flexible, is well matched with
an older man, who will indulge her tendency to test his love.
Her worst match?
Another only, of course.
Questions 22 to 25 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 22. What does the speaker say about Ronald and Lois's early years of
married life? Question 23.
What do we learn about Ronald and Lois?
Question 24. What does the speaker say about the oldest child in a
Question 25. What does the speaker say about the only children?
This is the end of listening comprehension.